Guide to the James Welch Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1962-2002; Series III; 4.38; (11 boxes)
  - Fletcher, John P., 1994-1995 (Box 38, Folder 598)
  - Flint Public Library, 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 599)
    Includes contract and itinerary
  - Florentine Films, 1993 Mar 29 (Box 38, Folder 600)
  - Fonds national d'art contemporain (France), 1996 May 9 (Box 38, Folder 601)
  - Ford, Richard, [1944-?], 1990-1996 (Box 38, Folder 602)
  - Fox, Richard A., 1995 Feb 3 (Box 38, Folder 603)
    Includes copy of review of Killing Custer by Fox
  - Freeman, Judith, 1997-1998 (Box 38, Folder 604)
  - Funk, Robert, 2000 Sep 6 (Box 38, Folder 605)
    Includes photograph
  - "G" General, 1975-2001, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 606-607)
  - Gallimard (Firm), 1996 Feb 15 (Box 38, Folder 608)
  - George, Stephen K., 2001 Jul 25 (Box 38, Folder 609)
  - Gerber, Dan, 1990-1999 (Box 38, Folder 610)
  - Germanacos, N.C., 1983-1991 (Box 38, Folder 611)
  - Gibson, Stan, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 612)
    Includes copy of review of Killing Custer by Gibson
  - Gildner, Gary, 1983 Aug 22 (Box 38, Folder 613)
  - Glenn Horowitz Bookseller (Firm), 1984 (Box 38, Folder 614)
    Includes copy of letter to Ripley Hugo
  - Governors State University, 1996 Mar 5 (Box 38, Folder 615)
  - Grilli, Giovanni, 1996-2001 (Box 38, Folder 616)
  - Guetti, James [L.?], 1976 Mar 10 (Box 38, Folder 617)
  - "H" General, 1987-2000, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 618-621)
    Includes draft of "The Scotsman who Died with Custer" by Herman Herst
  - Harjo, Joy, 1994 Dec 14 (Box 38, Folder 622)
  - Harleman, Ann, 2000 Mar 22 (Box 38, Folder 623)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, 1975-1983 (Box 38, Folder 624)
  - HarperCollins (Firm), 1992-1999 (Box 38, Folder 625)
  - Harper's, 1976 Jan 16 (Box 38, Folder 626)
  - Harris, Janice, 2001 Aug 28 (Box 38, Folder 627)
  - Hart, Jim, 1993 Oct 1 (Box 38, Folder 628)
  - Haruf, Kent, 1992-1999 (Box 38, Folder 629)
  - Hearle, Kevin, 1994 Nov 28 (Box 38, Folder 630)
  - Hellgate Writers, Inc., 1996-1997 (Box 38, Folder 631)
  - Henley, Patricia, 1995 Nov 29 (Box 38, Folder 632)
  - Hennepin County Library, 1995 Mar 10 (Box 38, Folder 633)
  - Herrin, Lamar, 2001 May 14 (Box 38, Folder 634)
  - Hoagland, Edward, 1990 Dec 28 (Box 38, Folder 635)
  - Hodgson, Heather, 1997 Aug 5 (Box 39, Folder 636)
  - Holcomb, Grant, 1991 Oct 8 (Box 39, Folder 637)
  - Hollatz, Tom, 1995 Mar 22 (Box 39, Folder 638)
  - Horsley, Jack E., 1995 (Box 39, Folder 639)
  - Hugo, Ripley S., 1984-1999 (Box 39, Folder 640)
    Includes photographs and clipping
  - Humbert Travel Agency, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 641)
  - Huston, Nancy, 1996 Apr 22 (Box 39, Folder 642)
  - "I" General, 1995-2000 (Box 39, Folder 643)
  - Idaho Library Association, 1993 Nov 8 (Box 39, Folder 644)
  - Illinois College, 2001 Sep 4 (Box 39, Folder 645)
  - International Biographical Centre, 1993 Jun 18 (Box 39, Folder 646)
  - Insignia Films, 1993-1995 (Box 39, Folder 647)
  - Institute of American Indian Arts, 1994 Apr 25 (Box 39, Folder 648)
  - Iowa State University. Dept. of English, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 649)
  - "J" General, 1982-1997 (Box 39, Folder 650)
  - Jejou, Alain, 1996 Mar 13 (Box 39, Folder 651)
  - Jones, Stephen [Graham?], 1999 Dec 11 (Box 39, Folder 652)
  - Josephy, Alvin M., 1996 Aug 5 (Box 39, Folder 653)
  - Jones, Allen, 2000 Sep 26 (Box 39, Folder 654)
  - "K" General, 1968-1999 (Box 39, Folder 655-656)
  - Kaplan, Frank L., 1994 Dec 29 (Box 39, Folder 657)
  - Key West Literary Seminar, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 658)
  - Krauzer, Steven M., 1987 May 15 (Box 39, Folder 659)
  - Krupat, Arnold, 1994 Feb 21 (Box 39, Folder 660)
  - "L" General, 1983-2001 (Box 39, Folder 661-663)
  - L.L. Bean, Inc., 1992 Mar (Box 39, Folder 664)
  - Lavender, David Sievert, 1992 Apr 4 (Box 39, Folder 665)
  - Lederer, Michel, 1991-2000, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 666)
  - Left Bank, 1992 Apr 10 (Box 39, Folder 667)
  - Lesley, Craig, 1992 Jan 14 (Box 39, Folder 668)
  - Lewis & Clark Library, 1999-2000 (Box 39, Folder 669)
  - Limberlost Press, 1999 Dec 27 (Box 39, Folder 670)
  - Lincoln, Kenneth, 1998 Sep 1 (Box 39, Folder 671)
    Includes outline for Sing with the Heart of a Bear
  - Lish, Gordon, 1977 Aug 26 (Box 39, Folder 672)
  - Lone Goose Press, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 673)
    Includes photocopy of "Thanksgiving at Snake Butte" by Welch
  - Lopez, Ken, 1994-1997 (Box 39, Folder 674)
    Includes biographical statement by Welch
  - Los Angeles Times (Firm), 2000 (Box 40, Folder 675)
  - Louis, Adrian C., 1994-1995 (Box 40, Folder 676)
  - Ludwig, Carol, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 677)
    Includes biographical statement for William Kittredge
  - Lupton, Mary Jane, 2001 Aug 18 (Box 40, Folder 678)
  - Luthin, Herbert W., 1994 Oct 30 (Box 40, Folder 679)
  - "M" General, 1969-2001, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 680-682)
  - Madden, Thomas, 1937-, 1995 Jan 16 (Box 40, Folder 683)
  - Manfred, Frederick Feikema, 1991 Apr 13 (Box 40, Folder 684)
  - The Manhattan Review, 1994-1995 (Box 40, Folder 685)
  - Mann, Henrietta, 2000 Jul 11 (Box 40, Folder 686)
  - Marchand, Jean, 1991 Aug 2 (Box 40, Folder 687)
  - Martin, Russell, 1991-1992 (Box 40, Folder 688)
  - Matthiessen, Peter, 1983 Dec 13 (Box 40, Folder 689)
  - Mayor, Adrienne, 1989 Aug 24 (Box 40, Folder 690)
  - McFadden, Cyra, 1990 Nov 11 (Box 40, Folder 691)
  - McFarland, Ronald E., 1999 (Box 40, Folder 692)
  - McGuane, Thomas, 1985 Feb 6 (Box 40, Folder 693)
  - Medicine, Beatrice, 2000 Oct 9 (Box 40, Folder 694)
  - Meli, Franco, 1992-1998 (Box 40, Folder 695)
  - Memphis State University, 1988 Aug 14 (Box 40, Folder 696)
  - Miami University (Oxford, Ohio), 1998 Sep 29 (Box 40, Folder 697)
  - Michaels, Leonard, 1933-, 1995 Jul 3 (Box 40, Folder 698)
  - Midge, Tiffany, 1993 Jun 22 (Box 40, Folder 699)
  - Midnight Films, 1992-2000, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 700)
  - Miles, George A., 1997 Mar 20 (Box 40, Folder 701)
  - Minneapolis Public Schools, 1992 Mar 20 (Box 40, Folder 702)
  - Minty, Judith, 1991 Nov 8 (Box 40, Folder 703)
  - Mirkowicz, Tomasz, 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 704)
  - Missoula County (Mont.). Detention Facility, 2001 Mar 28 (Box 40, Folder 705)
  - Missoula County (Mont.). Jury Commission, 1993-1999 (Box 40, Folder 706)
  - Momaday, N. Scott, 1979 Dec 20 (Box 40, Folder 707)
  - Montana, 1992-1994 (Box 40, Folder 708)
    Includes photocopies of photographs of Welch
  - Montana. Office of the Governor, 1979-1988 (Box 40, Folder 709)
  - Montana Committee for the Humannities, 1995-2001 (Box 40, Folder 710)
  - Montana State University--Billings, 1995-2000 (Box 40, Folder 711)
  - Montana State University--Bozeman, 1993-2001 (Box 41, Folder 712)
  - Moore, Michael S., 1998-1999 (Box 41, Folder 713)
  - [Morgan, Robert, 1944-?], 1991 Jan 3 (Box 41, Folder 714)
  - "N" General, 1984-1997 (Box 41, Folder 715)
  - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences, 1993 Jul 30 (Box 41, Folder 716)
  - National Council of Teachers of English, 1993-1994 (Box 41, Folder 717)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1995 Jan 8 (Box 41, Folder 718)
  - National Museum of American History, 1992 May 12 (Box 41, Folder 719)
  - National Public Radio, 1991 Jul 6 (Box 41, Folder 720)
  - Nature Conservancy, 1993-1994 (Box 41, Folder 721)
  - Nelson, Kent, 1991 Jan 13 (Box 41, Folder 722)
  - New Mexico State University, 1993 Jun 16 (Box 41, Folder 723)
  - New Prospect Productions, Inc., 1994-1995 (Box 41, Folder 724)
  - New School for Social Research, 1981 Apr 20 (Box 41, Folder 725)
  - New York Times, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 726)
  - Newberry Library, 1992 Feb 3 (Box 41, Folder 727)
  - Newby, Rick, 2000 Jun 18 (Box 41, Folder 728)
    Includes draft of "The West from Two Perspectives" by Welch
  - Newgarden, Albert, 1992-1999 (Box 41, Folder 729)
  - Newsweek, 1992 Jun 30 (Box 41, Folder 729a)
    Includes letter from Lois Welch
  - Niatum, Duane, 2001 Sep 7 (Box 41, Folder 730)
  - Northern Lights and Education Institute, 1989 Jan 30 (Box 41, Folder 731)
  - Northern State University, 1991-1994 (Box 41, Folder 732)
  - "O" General, 1993-2000 (Box 41, Folder 733)
  - O'Brien, Charles F., 1994 May 11 (Box 41, Folder 734)
  - Oliver's Books, 1993-1994 (Box 41, Folder 735)
  - Oregon State University, 1995 Nov 16 (Box 41, Folder 736)
  - Ortiz, Simon J., 1993-2000 (Box 41, Folder 737)
  - Orton, Thomas, 1992-2000 (Box 41, Folder 738)
  - Owens, Louis, 2001 Jul 3 (Box 41, Folder 739)
  - "P" General, 1987-2002, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 740-742)
  - Pack, Robert, 2001 Nov 13 (Box 41, Folder 743)
    Includes drafts of "Fire Season, 2000" and "October Larches" by Pack
  - Pantheon Books, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 744)
  - Patchett, Ann, 1994 Apr 7 (Box 41, Folder 745)
  - Pavlich, Walter, 1992, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 746)
  - Pellerin, Simone, 1992-1997 (Box 41, Folder 747)
  - Penguin (Firm), 1995, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 748)
  - Perry, Barbara, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 749)
  - Ploughshares, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 750)
  - Portland State University, 1992 Feb 17 (Box 42, Folder 751)
  - Price, Reynolds, 1978, 1998 (Box 42, Folder 752)
    Includes printed version of "Christ Child's Song at the End of the Night" by Price
  - Price, Richard, 1981 Aug 18 (Box 42, Folder 753)
  - Price, William, 1975 Dec 1 (Box 42, Folder 754)
  - Prud'hon, Martine, 1992-2000 (Box 42, Folder 755)
    Includes photographs of Welch and others
  - "Q" General, 1997 Jun 14 (Box 42, Folder 756)
  - Quivik, Fred, 2002 Jan 10 (Box 42, Folder 757)
  - "R" General, 1975-2000 (Box 42, Folder 758-759)
  - Radiotelevisione della Svizzera italiana, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 760)
  - Rago, Henry, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 761)
  - Random House (Firm), 1979-2000, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 762)
  - Rattlesnake Productions, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 763)
    Includes project description for Backbone of the World: The Blackfeet
  - Raynal, Patrick, 1993 Mar 17 (Box 42, Folder 764)
  - Renfer, Christoph, 2000, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 765)
  - Reisman, Nancy, 1996 May 12 (Box 42, Folder 766)
  - Richardson, Robert D., 1990-1995 (Box 42, Folder 767)
  - Roberts, Chris, 1948-, 1993 Feb 22 (Box 42, Folder 768)
    Includes copies of correspondence from National Geographic
  - Root, William Pitt, 1994 Apr 5 (Box 42, Folder 769)
    Includes draft of "Making Way" by Root
  - Ruoff, A. LaVonne Brown, 2000-2001 (Box 42, Folder 770)
  - Ryan, Mike, 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 771)
  - "S" General, 1981-2001 (Box 42, Folder 772-774)
  - Sadler, Jeff, 1991 Apr 22 (Box 42, Folder 775)
  - Salisbury, Ralph J., 1992 (Box 42, Folder 776)
  - Salmon Run Press, 1994 May 3 (Box 42, Folder 777)
  - Saturday Review, 1968 Apr 1 (Box 42, Folder 778)
  - Schiff, James A., 1995-1999 (Box 42, Folder 779)
  - Schubnell, Matthias, 1994 Mar 4 (Box 42, Folder 780)
  - Selbourne, Anthony, 1997 Jan 30 (Box 43, Folder 781)
  - Servid, Carolyn, 1999 Aug 23 (Box 43, Folder 782)
  - Silver Budette & Ginn (Firm), 1993 Aug 23 (Box 43, Folder 783)
  - Sledge, William H., 2000 Nov 2 (Box 43, Folder 784)
  - Smith, Annick, 1936-, 1987 Nov 16 (Box 43, Folder 785)
    Copy of letter from Smith to Sundance Film Institute
  - Snyder, Gary, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 786)
  - Solotaroff, Ted, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 787)
  - South Dakota State University, 1995 Oct 10 (Box 43, Folder 788)
  - Spaulding, Susan, 1995-2001, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 789)
  - St. Labre School students, 1999-2000 (Box 43, Folder 790)
  - St. Paul's School (Concord, N.H.), 1998 Feb 15 (Box 43, Folder 791)
  - Stekler, Paul, 1991 Jun 18 (Box 43, Folder 792)
  - Strandberg, Ingela, 1993-1994 (Box 43, Folder 793)
  - Sun Valley Writers' Conference, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 794)
    Includes photograph of Welch
  - Swetz van Middhlar, C. Wolfram, 1994-1996 (Box 43, Folder 795)
    Includes photograph of Swetz van Middhlar
  - "T" General, 1992-2000 (Box 43, Folder 796)
  - Tart, Indrek, 1988-1990 (Box 43, Folder 797)
  - Tate, [James?], 1975-1979 (Box 43, Folder 798)
  - Texas Christian University, 1994 Aug 9 (Box 43, Folder 799)
  - Trinity College (Hartford, Conn.), 2000 Dec 4 (Box 43, Folder 800)
  - "U" General, 1996 Sep 18 (Box 43, Folder 801)
  - Unger, Douglas, 1995 Aug 8 (Box 43, Folder 802)
  - United States. Information Agency, 1991 Nov 26 (Box 43, Folder 803)
  - United States Information Service (Rome, Italy), 1996 Jan 31 (Box 43, Folder 804)
  - United States. Internal Revenue Service 1997 Feb 3 (Box 43, Folder 805)
  - University of Alabama, 1993 Jun 22 (Box 43, Folder 806)
  - University of Arizona, 1992-1993 (Box 43, Folder 807)
  - University of British Columbia, 1997 Oct 7 (Box 43, Folder 808)
  - University of California, Riverside, 1992 Aug 20 (Box 43, Folder 809)
  - University of Chicago, 1997 Dec 30 (Box 43, Folder 810)
  - University of Hawaii at Manoa, 1992 Nov 28 (Box 43, Folder 811)
  - University of Idaho, 1991-2001 (Box 43, Folder 812)
  - University of Illinois at Chicago, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 813)
  - University of Iowa, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 814)
  - University of Iowa. International Writing Program, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 815)
  - University of Memphis, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 816)
  - University of Montana, 1989-1999 (Box 43, Folder 817)
  - University of Montana. Upward Bound Program, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 818)
  - University of Nebraska Press, 1991-2000 (Box 43, Folder 819)
    Includes draft of Introduction to Winter Wheat by Welch
  - University of Nevada, Las Vegas, 1994 Jan 10 (Box 43, Folder 820)
  - University of New Mexico, 1993 Jun 25 (Box 43, Folder 821)
  - University of North Alabama, 1992 Jun 12 (Box 43, Folder 822)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1992-2001 (Box 43, Folder 823)
  - University of Oregon, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 824)
  - University of Pisa, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 825)
  - University of Portland, 1999-2000 (Box 43, Folder 826)
  - University of Regina. Canadian Plains Research Center, 1995 Dec 18 (Box 43, Folder 827)
  - University of Utah, 1987-2001 (Box 43, Folder 828)
  - University of Washington, 1975-1991 (Box 43, Folder 829)
  - Unterberg Poetry Center, 1993-1995 (Box 44, Folder 830)
  - Utah State University, 1994 Apr 7 (Box 44, Folder 831)
  - "V" General, 1991-2001 (Box 44, Folder 832)
  - Valparaiso University, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 833)
  - Van Camp, Richard, 2000 May 6 (Box 44, Folder 834)
  - Vescey, Christopher, 1993 Oct 12 (Box 44, Folder 835)
    Includes draft of "The Story and Structure of the Iroquois Confederacy" by Vescey
  - Victor Gollancz Ltd., 1979 Jul 3 (Box 44, Folder 836)
  - Viking Penguin, 1985-1996 (Box 44, Folder 837)
  - "W" General, 1992-2001 (Box 44, Folder 838-840)
  - W. W. Norton & Company, 1984-2000, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 841-842)
  - Waltermire, Jay, 1981 Jan 28 (Box 44, Folder 843)
  - Warren Wilson College, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 844)
  - Washington University (St. Louis, Mo.), 1995 Apr 23 (Box 44, Folder 845)
  - Weber State University, 1992-2000 (Box 44, Folder 846)
  - Welch, Lois, 1996-1998, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 847)
    See also: Newsweek, Box 41, folder 729a
  - Welch, ----, n.y. Nov 9 (Box 44, Folder 848)
  - Western Carolina University, 1991 Dec 3 (Box 44, Folder 849)
  - WETA-TV (Television station: Washington, D.C.), 1991 Jul 16 (Box 44, Folder 850)
  - WGBH (Television station: Boston, Mass.), 1995-2001 (Box 44, Folder 851)
  - Whiteman, Roberta Hill, 1995-1996 (Box 44, Folder 852)
  - Wildlife Management Institute, 1995 Mar 21 (Box 44, Folder 853)
  - Willis, Patricia C., 2000 (Box 44, Folder 854)
  - WNET (Television Station: New York, N.Y.), 2000 Jul 27 (Box 44, Folder 855)
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1992-1994 (Box 44, Folder 856)
  - Woody, Elizabeth, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 857)
  - World Publishing Company, 1973 Mar 20 (Box 44, Folder 858)
  - Writers' Forum, 1994 Aug 19 (Box 44, Folder 859)
  - Writers Guild of America, 1995-1998 (Box 44, Folder 860)
  - "Y" General, 1982, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 861)
  - Young Bear, Ray, 1990, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 862)
  - First name only, 1962-2001, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 863-867)
  - Unidentified, 1976-2000, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 868)
  - Empty Envelopes, 1975-1994 (Box 45, Folder 869)
- Personal Papers, 1956-2002; Series IV; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers, is organized into four subseries: Financial Records, Printed Material, School Material, and Other.
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Financial records, 1974-1998, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 870-876)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Clippings, periodicals, and printouts
      - The Death of Jim Loney, 1980, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 877)
      - Fools Crow, 1987-2002, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 878-881)
      - The Heartsong of Charging Elk, 2000-2001, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 882-886)
        Includes printouts of third-party correspondence
      - The Indian Lawyer, 1989, 2000 (Box 46, Folder 887)
      - Riding the Earthboy 40, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 888)
      - Winter in the Blood, 1987, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 889)
      - Killing Custer, 1994 Dec
      - General interest clippings on James Welch and other topics, 1968-2001, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 890)
    - Conference and Event Materials
      - Browning High School commencement, 1993 May 30 (Box 47, Folder 891)
      - Key West Literary Seminar, 1995-1996 (Box 47, Folder 892-893)
        Includes correspondence
      - Paris book fair, 1996 Mar (Box 47, Folder 894)
      - Sun Valley Writers' Conference, 1997 Aug (Box 47, Folder 895-896)
      - Università IULM, 1998 Dec (Box 47, Folder 897)
      - University of Montana commencements, 1997-2001 (Box 47, Folder 898-899)
    - Other Material
      - Announcements and invitations, 1973-2001, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 900)
      - Bookmarks, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 901)
      - Brochures, catalogs, and programs, 1962-2002, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 902-904)
      - Business cards, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 905)
      - Maps, 1960, n.d.
      - Periodicals, 1994-2001 (Box 47, Folder 906-908)
      - Postcards, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 909)
      - Other, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 910)
  - SCHOOL MATERIAL
    - Course documents, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 911)
    - Essays and papers, 1964-1968, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 912-913)
    - [Loose] notes, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 914)
    - Notebooks, [ca. 1962-1968] (Box 48, Folder 915-922)
    - Notebooks, [ca. 1962-1968] (Box 49, Folder 923-930)
    - Notebooks, [ca. 1962-1968] (Box 49, Folder 931-932)
    - Plays, 1967, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 933)
    - Records, 1956-1964, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 934)
    - Short stories, 1963-1965, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 935)
    - Tests, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 936)
  - OTHER
    - Biographical material, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 937)
    - Contracts, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 938)
    - "Indian World" Show, PDX OR, with DJ Spider Moccasin, KBOO 90.7 FM [Sound recording] (Box 50, Folder 939)
    - Itineraries and schedules, 1975-2001 (Box 50, Folder 940-941)
    - Lists, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 942)
    - [Loose] notes, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 943)
    - Passport, 1985 May 20 (Box 50, Folder 944)
    - Photographs, 1980, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 945)
- Oversize, 6.35; (3 boxes)
  - Layout for final draft of The Death of Jim Loney (In Series I), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 946)
  - Notes to Fools Crow (In Series I), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 947)
  - Photocopy of map proof of Fools Crow (In Series I), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 948)
  - Background material to The Heartsong of Charging Elk (In Series I), 1889-1993, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 949)
  - Wrapper to The Indian Lawyer (In Series I) (Box 51, Folder 950)
  - [Empty box] (Box 52)
  - Printer's proof to Winter in the Blood (In Series I), 1974 (Box 53, Folder 951)
  - Galley proof of Winter in the Blood (In Series I), 1974 (Box 53, Folder 952)
  - Master proof of Riding the Earthboy 40 (In Series I), 1971 (Box 53, Folder 955)
  - Galley proof of Riding the Earthboy 40 (In Series I), 1971 (Box 53, Folder 956)
  - First proof of jacket copy for Winter in the Blood (In Series I), 1974 Aug 15 (Box 54, Folder 953)
  - Wrapper for Winter in the Blood (In Series I), n.d. (Box 54, Folder 954)
  - Wrapper to poems by James Welch (In Series I), [1974?] (Box 54, Folder 957)
  - Wrapper for Killing Custer (In Series I), n.d. (Box 54, Folder 958)
  - Reproduction of book jacket for Killing Custer (In Series I), n.d. (Box 54, Folder 959)
  - [Empty folder] (Box 54, Folder 960)
  - Clippings on Fools Crow (In Series IV) (Box 54, Folder 961-962)
  - Clippings on The Heartsong of Charging Elk (In Series IV), 2000-2001 (Box 54, Folder 963-964)
  - Clippings on The Indian Lawyer (In Series IV), 2000 Sep 2 (Box 54, Folder 965)
  - Clippings on Killing Custer (In Series IV), 1944 Dec (Box 54, Folder 966)
  - Clippings on James Welch and other topics (In Series IV), 1968-2002, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 967-968)
  - Clippings on Key West conference (In Series IV), 1996 Jan 11 (Box 54, Folder 969)
  - Printed announcements (In Series IV), 1988 (Box 54, Folder 970)
  - Printed maps (In Series IV), 1960, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 971)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.42; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Computer disks (In Series I) (Box 55, Folder 972-979)
  - Computer disks (In Series I) (Box 55, Folder 980-987)
  - Computer disks (In Series I) (Box 55, Folder 988-995)
  - Computer disks (In Series II-III) (Box 55, Folder 996-997)